Guide to the John E. Fleming Papers, 1962-2013 RL.11014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Personal, 1965-2011; 21
  - Funeral arrangements and other details for James E. Fleming, 2010 (Box 35)
  - John W. Fleming materials, 1980s-2000s (Box 35)
  - Chicago Historical Society interview, 2005 June 27 (Box 35)
  - White House Fellowship application, 1983 (Box 35)
  - NC State Musuem application, 2000 (Box 35)
  - University of Maryland Driskell Center application, 2001 (Box 35)
  - Indiana Historical Society Application, 2000 (Box 35)
  - Oral history interview re: Berea College and March to Selma, 2004 June 17 (Box 35)
  - Handwritten diary pages, 2010-2012 (Box 35)
  - Clippings saved by JEF, 1970s-2000s (Box 35)
  - Awards, certificates, 1970s-2010s (Box 35)
  - Olive Hill High School, 1980s-1990s (Box 35)
  - Resumes/bios, 1999-2001 (Box 35)
  - Camp Martin Johnson, 1965 (Box 35)
  - Calendars, date books, 1970s (Box 35)
  - Calendars, date books, 1999-2000, 2008 (Box 35)
- Correspondence, 1963-2013; 22
  The majority of this series consists of Fleming's correspondence, both personal and professional, which has been loosely arranged by year. Three files at the end of the series are segregated by subject, representing how they were originally donated to the Rubenstein: Fleming's correspondence with Berea College; Fleming's correspondence with Mary Ann Olding over her dissertation process; and Fleming's correspondence about the Selective Service and his status as a Conscientious Objector during the Vietnam War.
  - Correspondence, 1967-1996; 31 folders (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, 1997-2013; 17 folders (Box 37)
  - Correspondence, undated; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Berea correspondence, 1986-1995, undated (Box 37)
  - re: Mary Ann Olding dissertation, 2003-2004 (Box 37)
  - re: Selective Service/Conscientious Objector, 1963-1969 (Box 37)
- Miscellaneous Audiovisual Materials, 1960s-2000s; 2
  - untitled, circa 1960s; 39
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 41, Audio-reel RL11014-RR-0001)
  - Black Memo interview with Dr. John Fleming, 1999-06-13; 40
    - VHS video (Box 41, Video-cassette RL11014-VHS-0003)
  - NPR, Morning Edition, Hour 2, 1999-10-07; 41
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0020)
  - National Underground Railroad Freedom Center, Lighting Freedom's Flame, 2000-07; 42
    - VHS video (Box 41, Video-cassette RL11014-VHS-0005)
    - VHS video (Box 41, Video-cassette RL11014-VHS-0007)
  - Freedom Center Architecture, news packages for museum opening, 2000-11-22; 43
    - VHS video (Box 41, Video-cassette RL11014-VHS-0004)
  - Liberty on the Border, Cincinnati Museum Center exhibit, 2003; 44
    - VHS video overview (Box 41, Video-cassette RL11014-VHS-0001)
    - Compact disc, exhibit images (Box 41, Data-cd RL11014-CDR-0002)
  - John Hope Franklin, CMC Distinguished Historian Lecture, images, 2006-04-20; 45
    - Compact disc (Box 41, Data-cd RL11014-CDR-0001)
  - Reflections on Carter G. Woodson, with John Hope Franklin and Adelaide M. Cromwell, 2007; 46
    - DVD video (Box 41, Video-disc RL11014-DVD-0002)
  - IAAM draft fundraising video, 2010-08-04; 47
    - Compact disc (Box 41, Data-cd RL11014-CDR-0003)
  - International African American Museum, 2010-10-27; 48
    - DVD video (Box 41, Video-disc RL11014-DVD-0001)
  - Songs, undated; 49
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0019)
  - Rosa Parks, undated; 50
    - VHS video (Box 41, Video-cassette RL11014-VHS-0006)
  - National Afro-American Museum and Cultural Center (exhibition), undated; 51
    - VHS video (Box 41, Video-cassette RL11014-VHS-0008)
  - Focus - John Fleming, undated; 52
    - VHS video (Box 41, Video-cassette RL11014-VHS-0002)